Guide to the Leopold Haimson papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence,1950s-1990s
  - Subseries I.2: General Correspondence, 1959-1997
    - Pipes, Richard, 1960-1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      (More of Pipes' correspondence see also: Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--Advisory Committee, Box 14, Folder 8-9. Photocopies of his letters to Belopol'skii of 1963see Series XI: Writings by Others--Subseries XI.2: Academic and professional works--Belopol'skii, Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Pollak, Nancy, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pollard, Alan, 1966-1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pomper, Philip, 1960-1976 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Proffer, Carl, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Rabinowitch, Alexander, 1960-1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Raeff, Marc, 1959-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Reberiaux, Madeleine, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Rieber, Alfred, 1972-1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Rittersporn, Gabor, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Robbins, Richard, 1971-1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Robert, Jean-Louis, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Roberts, Henry, 1964-1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      (See also correspondence of 1959 and 1961 Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--Chronological correspondence, Box 14, Folders 1-7)
    - Rogger, Hans, 1959-1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Roosa, Ruth, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Roosevelt, Priscilla, 1975-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Rosenberg, William, 1970-1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rosenhan, Mollie, 1964, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rosenthal, Bernice, 1976-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rublev, Michel, 1970-1977 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Ruckman, Jo Ann, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Sablinsky, Walter, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sammer, Jan, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sanders, Jonathan, 1974-1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Sapelli, Giulio, 1984-1997see Fondazione Giangiacomo Feltrinelli
    - Schatoff, Michael, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Scherrer, Jutta, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Segal-Meler, Louis, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Shanin, Theodore, 1973-1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Shatz, Marshall, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Shecket, Alexandra, 1968-1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Shevchenko, Ihor, 1968 see Series V: Seminars--Subseries V.1: Columbia University Seminars--1968-1969 School Year--Correspondence (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Shukman, Harry, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Shulman, Marshall, 1969-1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Siegelbaum, Lewis, 1971-1989 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Silver, Patricia, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Solotaroff, Lynn, 1965-1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      (See also letters of 1971 Series III: Menshevik Project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--General--Mensheviks interviews correspondence, Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Spalding, Karen, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - St. Antony's College, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Suny, Ronald, 1967-1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Surh, Gerald, 1979-1997 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Tilly, Charles, 1981-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Tschistaganow, Lilia, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Overseas Projects Section, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ulam, Adam, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - University microfilm, 1965-1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - University of California, 1959-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      (re: Haimson's appointment)
    - Valkenier, Elizabeth, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Vinaver, Eugene, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Vinogradov, Eugene, 1966-1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Vladimirskaia, Zhanna, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Wcislo, Frank, 1981-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Werth, Nicolas, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Wiener, Douglas, 1979-1987 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Wildman, Allan, 1960-1993 (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
    - Wortman, Richard, 1960-1986 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
      (See also his correspondence of 1974-1977 Series III: Menshevik Project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--General--Mensheviks interviews correspondence, Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Zelnik, Reginald, 1964-1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Zimmerman, Judith, 1967-1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Subseries I.3: Chronological Correspondence, 1955-1997
    Files contain incoming and outgoing small volume correspondence. Arranged chronologically by year and then alphabetically within the year.
    - undated, 1955, 1958, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1972 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 1984-1997 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.4: Subject Correspondence, 1959-1999
    This subseries is organized into three sub-subseries.
    - Sub-subseries I.4.1: Invitations for Lectures and Conferences, 1960-1997
      Invitations from various universities and other academic institutions. Includes related correspondence. Arranged in chronological order.
      - 1960-1965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - 1972-1997 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Sub-subseries I.4.2: Letters of Recommendation, 1959-1999
      Recommendations for students and colleagues, with related correspondence. Organized alphabetically by the last name of the recommended person. Group recommendations, which contain recommendations for more than one person, stored at the end of the sub-subseries. More letters of recommendation filed throughout the collection and can be found in the correspondence and student files
      - A (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - B (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - C (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - D (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - E (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - F (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - G (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - H-J (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - K (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - L (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - M (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - N-R (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Sc-Sp (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - St-Sw (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - T (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - V-Z (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Group recommendations (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
        (letters contain recommendations for more than one person)
    - Sub-subseries I.4.3: Correspondence with Publishers, 1959-1991
      Comprises letters, book reviews, reader reports, memorandums, agreements, and project proposals. Organized in alphabetical order by the name of the publisher.
      - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - American Historical Review, 1960-1982
        - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - Manuscript: Anfimov, A. "Krest'ainstvo v Rossii v 1907-1914gg." (Box 11, Folder 2)
          (English translation The Russian peasantry, 1907-1914 by B.Travis)
      - American Peoples Encyclopedia, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - American Political Science Review, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - American Slavic and East European Review: see Slavic Review
      - Atheneum Publishers, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Basic Books, Inc., 1981 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Beacon Press, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Beamur International Ltd., 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Bedford Publications, Inc., undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Bobbs-Merrill Reprints, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Cambridge University Press, 1981-1991 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Collier & Son Corporation: see P.F.Collier&Son Corporation
      - Columbia University Forum, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Columbia University Press, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Comprehensive Graphics, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 7)
        (re: Strikes, War, and Revoliution)
      - Daedalus, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Foreign Affairs: American Quarterly Review, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Giulio Einaudi Editore, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Grolier Society, Inc., 1961 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Harper & Row, Publishers, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Harvard University Press, 1955-1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Historian, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Indiana University Press, 1977-1988 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - John Wiley and Sons, Inc., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Journal of Contemporary History, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Journal of Modern History, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 13)
        (See also correspondence of 1975 regarding the publication of Mensheviks: Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--General--Publications, Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Journal of Social History, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Knopf: see Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
      - Labor History, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - McGrow-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - McGrow-Hill Encyclopedia of World Biography, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Monad Press, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Norton & Company, Inc: see W.W. Norton & Company, Inc.
      - Ohio University Press, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Open University, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Oxford University Press, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - P.F.Collier&Son Corporation, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Pantheon Press, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Passato e Presente, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Political Science Quarterly, 1959-1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Press of Western Reserve University, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Princeton University Press, 1975-1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
        (See also correspondence of 1971-1972 regarding the publication of Mensheviks: Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--General--Publications, Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Random House, Inc., 1970 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Revolutionary Russia (former Sbornik), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Richard Abel & Co., Inc., 1963 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Russian Review, 1979-1989 (Box 11, Folder 16)
        (See also: correspondence with Daniel Field, Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Slavic Review, 1960-1988 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Soviet Studies, 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - St. Martin's Press, Inc., 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Stanford University Press, 1965-1980 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - State University of New York Press, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Survey, 1961-1966 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Ulbandus Review, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - United States Information Agency, 1960,1962 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - University of California Press, 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - University of Chicago Press, 1960-1966 (Box 11, Folder 21)
        (See also correspondence of 1959-1977 regarding the publication of the volume Mensheviks: Series III: Menshevik Project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--General--Publications, Box 16, Folders 2-6)
      - University of Michigan Press, 1961-1974 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - University of North Carolina Press, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - University of Notre Dame Press, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - University of Wisconsin Press, 1969-1979 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - University Press of Kansas, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Vintage Books, Inc., 1960 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - W.W. Norton & Company Inc., 1977-1986 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Wesleyan University Press, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Westvew Press, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Wheatsbeaf Books Ltd., 1987 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Yale University Press, 1964-1969 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Series II: Writings, 1951-1994
  This series includes monographs, articles, papers given at conferences, interviews, and book reviews by Leopold Haimson. Mostly typescripts and photocopies of typescripts, often with holograph corrections and notes by the author; also includes reprints, publications, and clippings. Arranged alphabetically by title. For more of Haimson's writings, see also: Series VII: Editorial Activities; Series X: Research and Reference Materials--Subseries X.2: Drafts and research notes; Series XI: Writings by Others--Subseries XI.3: Unidentified writings.
  - Articles, monographs, interviews, papers
    - "Alexander Erlich," 1985, (obituary; photocopy of typescript, reprint) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Annexe I: Ouvrages sur la revolution de 1917 sous les auspices de la Commission Internationale pour des projets de collaboration en histoire de la Russie contemporaine, publies recemment en France avec l'appui de la MSH et distributes en France pa la MSH (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Annexe II: Memorandum pour Albin Michel (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - changements demographiques et greves ouvrieres a Saint-Petersbourg," 1905-1914, 1985, (reprint) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - crisis of Soviet system," 1981-1982, (article for Le Monde: drafts, outline, related correspondence) (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - "Greves ouvrieres en Russie imperiale pendant la Premiere Guerre mondiale et le declenchement de la revolution de fevrier 1917" (Box 12, Folder 5-A)
      (in co-authorship with E.Brian; reprint)
    - "Henry L. Roberts," 1916-1972In memoriam, (typescript, galleys proof, drafts) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Interview with Dr. Reuben Fine, 1951, (typescript with holograph corrections; with related material) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Istoricheskie korni Fevral'skoi revoliutsii," 1994, (photocopy of publication) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "K voprosu o politicheskoi i sotsial'noi identifikatsii rabochikh Rossii v kontse XIX-go - nachale XX-go vekov: rol' v obshchestvennykh otnosheniiakh uchastnikov rabochego dvizheniia s sotsial-demokraticheskoi intelligentsiei", (photocopy of typescript) (Box 12, Folder 9)
      (in co-authorship with Erid Brian)
    - "Labor unrest in Imperial Russia during the First World War: a quantitative analysis and interpretation", (photocopy of typescript) (Box 12, Folder 10)
      (in co-authorship with Eric Brian)
    - "Menshevik leaders and the problem of power during the revolutions of 1917," 1997 (Box 12, Folder 10-A)
      (with related letter)
    - "Mensheviks after the October Revolution"
      - Part I, 1979, (reprint) (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Part II: The Extraordinary Party Congress
        - Manuscript, (typescript and photocopy of typescript) (Box 12, Folder 12-13)
          (incomplete)
        - Reprint, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "Menscheviks face a la Revolution d'Octobre: le Congres extraordinaire du RSDRP, novembre-decembre 1917", (reprint) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "Observations on additional statistical tables and final regression equations of quantitative analysis of industrial labor conflicts in Imperial Russia during the First World War, August 1914-February 1917", (photocopy of typescript) (Box 12, Folder 16)
      (See also: Series VI: Colloquia and Conferences--1986--New Orleans, Box 87, Folder 4)
    - "Parties and the state: the evolution of political attitudes in post-emancipation Russia," 1960, (carbon copy with holograph corrections and reprint) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "Peasant elections to the Second and Third Duma", (photocopy of typescript) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "Peasantry in 1905", (photocopy of typescript) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Preface to "The making of a workers' revolution" by Allan Wildman (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "Problem of social stability in urban Russia, 1905-1917," 1965, (reprints) (Box 13, Folder 5)
      (in English and German)
    - "Razvitie politicheskogo i sotsial'nogo krizisa v Rossii v period ot kanuna Pervoi mirovoi voiny do Fevral'skoi revoliutsii", (typescript) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "Reply," 1965, (reprint) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "Russian culture and Western liberalism," 1976, (publication) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "Russian intelligentsia," 1960, (reprint) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "Russian workers' movement on the eve of the First World War," 1971, (photocopy of typescript, draft) (Box 13, Folder 10-12)
      (paper given at the AHA meeting)
    - "Solitary hero and the Philistines: a note on the heritage of the Stalin era", (reprint) (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - "Three generations of the Soviet intelligentsia," 1959, (reprint) (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "Workers movement in Russia after Lena," 1986, (typescript with holograph notes) (Box 13, Folder 15-17)
  - Book reviews and readers reports: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.4: Subject Correspondence--Publishers (Box 11)
  - Prefaces and forewords to writings by Mensheviks: see Series III: Menshevik project--Sub-subseries III.3.3: Writings and publications (Boxes 41-50)
- Series III: Menshevik Project,1890s-1977(Inter-University Project on the History of Menshevik Movement)
  This series consists of materials of the Inter-University Project on the History of the Menshevik Movement. The project was launched in the fall of 1959, with the support of the Ford Foundation, by an ad hoc committee of specialists in Russian history teaching at American universities, in collaboration with representatives of the then already fast dwindling Menshevik émigré community in the United States. (The subsequent work of the project was also supported by grants from the Rockefeller and Atran foundations, the Hoover Institution, and the American Council of Learned Societies.)
  The Project pursued two main goals: to assemble and preserve the factual record, and to provide a suitable medium for survivors of the Menshevik movement to re-examine those aspects of the Party's history in which they had been most directly involved.
  The pursuit of these two objectives culminated in the establishment of a permanent archive on the history of Menshevism; the preparation, and distribution in multilith form, of accounts by Mensheviks residing in the United States and Western Europe of events in the Party's history in which they were participants; and preparation for publication of memoirs, bibliographies, and documentary and monographic studies by Menshevik associates of the Project as well as participating American scholars. English language volumes are being published by the University of Chicago Press; others appeared in a Russian-language series sponsored by the Hoover Institution.
  The series is arranged in three subseries, then in sub-subseries within them.
  - Subseries III.1: Project Records, 1957-1977
    This subseries includes documentation of the Project including correspondence, documents, grant files, and other project records. Arranged by type of material.
    - Subsubseries III.1.1: Correspondence, 1959-1977
      The Project's incoming and outgoing correspondence with various people and organizations. Also included are related materials, such as manuscripts, clippings, receipts, etc. Sub-subseries divided on chronological and general correspondence. Chronological part includes mainly the correspondence of M.L. Nelson (project secretary), Ladis K.D. Kristoff (associate director), Helen Forsythe, and Leopold Haimson with various organizations and people. General correspondence is arranged alphabetically by subject and correspondent name. More related correspondence is filed under various involved persons' names in Series I: Correspondence
      - Chronological correspondence, 1959-1970:
        - 1959 (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - 1960 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - 1961 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
        - 1962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - 1963 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - 1964-1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - General correspondence:
        - Advisory Committee correspondence, 1958-1963
          - Circular letters (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Barghoorn, F. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Black, C. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Byrnes, R. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Dallin, Alexandr: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.2: General Correspondence--Dallin (Box 2, Folder 3)
          - Fainsod, M. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Inkeles, A. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Malia, M. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Pipes, R. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Roberts, Henry (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
          - Treatgold, D. (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
        - Amsterdam, International Institute of Social History, 1959-1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Blit, Lucien, 1960 see Amsterdam, International Institute of Social History
        - British Museum, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Bund Archive, 1961-1963 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Butler Library, 1959-1969 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - Gramont, Dumesnil, de, undated, 1959-1963 (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
        - Haimson, Leopold - L. Kristoff correspondence, 1959-1974 (Box 15, Folder 4-6)
        - Helsinki University Library and Helsinki Library Recolid, 1959-1966 (Box 15, Folder 7)
        - Henry F.Grieme Incorporated Insurance (aka Grieme, Darling & Ayres, Inc.), 1959-1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - Heroys, H., 1959-1963 (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - Hoover Institution, 1959-1971 (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
        - Interviews correspondence: see Mensheviks interviews correspondence (Box 15, Folders 14)
        - Kamermakher, Iuliia: see her Project related correspondence with various people in: Subseries III.2: Mensheviks personal files--Sub-subseries III.2.1: Correspondence and documents--Kamermakher, Iuliia (Box 20, Folders 13-16 and Box 21, Folders 1-10)
        - Kristoff, Ladis - L. Haimson correspondence: see Haimson, Leopold - L. Kristoff correspondence (Box 15, Folders 4-6)
        - Library:
          - Library of Congress, 1960-1966 (Box 15, Folder 12)
          - University of Chicago Library, 1959-1963 (Box 15, Folder 13)
            (See also: Series VIII: Institutional Files--Subseries 1: Chicago University Files--Library, Box 89, Folder 8)
          - University of Illinois Library, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 13)
          - Yale University Library, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 13)
        - Minkov, Isai, 1964-1966see Sub-subseries III.1.4: Grant files--Atran Foundation (Box 18, Folders 8-9)
        - Mensheviks interviews correspondence, 1974-1977:
          - American Council of Learned Societies, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 14)
          - Lopez-Morillas, M., 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 14)
          - Solotaroff, Lynn, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 14)
          - Stanford University, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 14)
          - Wortman, Richard, 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 14)
        - Nesterova, S.: see Gramont, Dumesnil (Box 15, Folders 2-3)
        - Nowicki, Maria (aka Novitskaia Mariia), 1959-1962 (Box 15, Folder 15)
        - Publications:
          - Distribution, 1960-1967 (Box 15, Folder 16)
          - General, 1959-1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
          - Journal of Modern History, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 1)
          - Princeton University Press, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
          - University of Chicago Press, 1959-1977 (Box 16, Folder 2-6)
        - Service International de Microfilms, 1960-1964 (Box 16, Folder 7)
        - Stockholm University, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 8)
        - Taxes, customs, duties, 1960-1963 (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - Vakar, Gertruda correspondence, 1962-1973
          (mostly correspondence with Project officials; arranged alphabetically by correspondent name. Also included 1 Folder of correspondence between project officials and her daughters)